Register of the Baronessa Marii͡a Dmitrievna Vrangel' collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Baronessa Marii͡a Dmitrievna Vrangel' collection
1915-1944
33003
Hoover Institution Archives
49 manuscript boxes, 12 oversize boxes (32.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, memoirs, biographical material, pamphlets, periodicals, newspapers, photographs, clippings, and printed matter relating to Russian émigré activities following the Russian Revolution and Civil War, including political, military, veterans', religious, educational, cultural, literary, artistic, and social activities. Includes a few papers of M. D. Vrangel'. Also available on microfilm (49 reels). Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Vrangel', Marii͡a Dmitrievna, baronessa, 1857-1944, collector.
Access
Microfilm use only (except for magazine and photographs that have not been microfilmed, as noted in container list). Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1933.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (49 reels). Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Historical Note
This collection was created by Baronessa Marii͡a Vrangel', mother of Baron Petr Nikolaevich Vrangel', last commander of the White Army, as a memorial to the cultural, academic and social contributions of the so-called first Russian emigration. This group was formed by individuals who emigrated from Russia after the defeat of the White Movement in the early 1920s and included many prominent representatives of the cultural and political elite of Imperial Russia.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, memoirs, biographical material, pamphlets, periodicals, newspapers, photographs, clippings, and printed matter relating to Russian émigré activities following the Russian Revolution and Civil War, including political, military, veterans', religious, educational, cultural, literary, artistic, and social activities. Includes a few papers of M. D. Vrangel'.
The collection incorporates a great variety of material, including biographical information which Baronessa Vrangel' solicited from individuals, as well as organizations active in the émigré community, personal correspondence, short biographies and autobiographies, memoirs, original and printed works, as well as photographs. There is also a large volume of clippings from the contemporary émigré press.
The collection consists of two parts: the first is arranged by the profession or field of activity of an individual or organization; this includes writers, artists, and academics, as well as social and professional organizations. The second is arranged by geographical location and includes material about émigré communities scattered around the globe.
Russia--Emigration and immigration.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Refugees.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Veterans.; Russia--Civilization.; Russian literature.; Russkai͡a pravoslavnai͡a t͡serkovʹ.
- Inventories, 1924-1944 (Boxes 1-2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Notebooks listing material contained in the collection "ZHivaia Letopis' Zhivykh." Part I includes alphabetical listings of individuals by profession or field of activity; Part II is organized according to place of residence. Also included are lists of printed matter deposited at the Hoover Institution Library.
  - Preface, typescript and handwritten, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Access
    Available on microfilm reel 1
  - Introduction, "Kak sozdavalsia moi arkhiv," typescript, 1933 May (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "ZHivaia Letopis' ZHivykh"
    - Part I, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
      Alphabetical listing of individuals and organizations prominent in Russian émigré cultural and intellectual life from 1917-1933, organized by profession or field of activity, handwritten and copy.
    - Part II, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
      Available on microfilm reel 2
      Alphabetical listing of individuals and organizations by place of residence, handwritten and copy.
  - Inventory of material re Belgium, handwritten, 1927-1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lists of additional material deposited at Hoover Institution, handwritten
    Includes personal papers, correspondence and printed matter.
    - 1924-1932 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Printed matter, newspapers, journals and books deposited at Hoover Institution Library, handwritten notebooks, 1924-1932, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sample request form for information, printed copy, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Responses to Baroness M. Vrangel's work, mostly clippings (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Part I (Boxes 2-38)
  - File 1, 1880s-1942
    Personal papers of Baroness Mariia Vrangel'. Includes documents, correspondence, and memoir.
    - Personal papers of Baroness M. Vrangel', official documents
      - Passports of Baroness M. Vrangel' and Baron N. Vrangel', 1905 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Last will and testament of Baron N. Vrangel' and power of attorney granted to Baroness M. Vrangel', typescript and handwritten, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Commercial documents re oil refinery in Vladikavkaz, 1880s-1920s (Box 2, Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 3
      - Correspondence
        - Family correspondence, 1930-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Personal business correspondence, 1922-1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Lists of correspondents, including those in categories below, handwritten, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Autograph book (File 35), 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Memoirs of Baroness M. Vrangel' re her life in Soviet Russia and escape abroad (1918-1920), handwritten, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Notebooks, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - File 2 (Boxes 3-4)
    The Russian Orthodox Church in exile. Includes correspondence and printed matter.
    - Russian Orthodox Church, printed matter and correspondence, 1922-1932
      - Australia (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 4
      - Belgium, especially building of Nicholas II Memorial Chapel (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Bulgaria (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - China (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Czechoslovakia
        - General (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Sergii, Archbishop (A. Korolev), biography (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - 1935 September
      - Estonia (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Finland (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - France (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Germany (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Greece (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Latvia, especially Archbishop Ioann (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - South America (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - United States (Box 4, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 5
      - Yugoslavia (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous material re schism of church abroad (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - File 3 (Box 4)
    - Russian Orthodox Church, printed matter and correspondence, 1926-1932
      - Theological Institute in Paris, printed matter (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Seminary, Monastery of St. Kirik, Bulgaria (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Monasteries, especially Pechery, Estonia (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Newspaper clippings, including TSarskii Vestnik, 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
        Available on microfilm reels 5-6
  - File 4, 1928-1933 (Box 5)
    Old Believers. Includes correspondence and printed matter.
    - Old Believers
      - Rodnaia Starina, 1928-1932 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 6
      - Vestnik Vysshago Staroobriadcheskago Soveta v Pol'she, 1929-1932 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Clippings and correspondence, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - File 5, 1917-1938 (Boxes 5-9)
    Leaders of the White Movement and R.O.V.S. (Russkii Obshche-Voinskii Soiuz). Includes correspondence, biographical and autobiographical material, printed matter, and clippings.
    - Leaders of the White Movement
      - Vrangel', Baron P.
        - Printed matter
          - Davats, V. and L'vov, N., Russkaia Armiia na CHuzhbine, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 4)
          - Dnevnik Generala M.G. Drozdovskago, 1923 (Box 5, Folder 5)
          - Pravosudie v Voiskakh Generala Vrangelia, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 6)
          - Russkaia Armiia v Izgnanii, 1920-1923 (Box 5, Folder 7)
          - Vozrozhdenie Russkoi Armii, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - Posters, undated (Map-case case)
          - Lubok style, commemorating taking of TSaritsyn
          - Leaders of the White Movement
        - Life abroad, 1920-1928
          - Miscellaneous material, including orders (Box 5, Folder 9)
          - Speech, Brussels, Russian and French version, typescript, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        - Death and funeral, miscellaneous material, including printed matter, clippings, letters of condolence and speeches at anniversaries of his death, 1928-1938 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
          Available on microfilm reel 7
    - Russkii Obshche-Voinskii Soiuz (R.O.V.S.) and participants in White Movement
      - Correspondence, includes biographical material and memoirs
        - General, April 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - Angileev, Maj.-Gen. V., undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - Arkhangel'skii, Lieut.-Gen. A., includes material re judicial investigation, March 1919-June 1932 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - Bagretsov, Col. S., January 1933 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - Barbovich, Lieut.-Gen. I., July 1931-January 1934 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Bazarevich, Col. V., March 1932 (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Beliaev, Gen. N., April 1932 (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Boltunov, Maj.-Gen. A., September 1917-October 1932 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Bredov, Lieut.-Gen., N., September 1932 (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - Brzhezitskii, Col. A., 1932 (Box 6, Folder 14)
        - Buturlin, M., 1920 (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - CHekotovskii, Maj.-Gen. I., February 1933 (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - CHernavin, Maj.-Gen. V., August 1932 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - Danilov, Gen.-of-Infantry, IU., August 1931 (Box 6, Folder 18)
        - Deitrich, V., January 1932 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - Domanevskii, Maj.-Gen. V., October 1931-May 1932 (Box 6, Folder 20)
        - Drozdovskii, Maj.-Gen. M., Vestnik Gallipoliitsev v Bolgarii, March, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        - Emelianov, Col. E., April 1936 (Box 6, Folder 22)
        - Erdeli, Gen. I., January 1932 (Box 6, Folder 23)
        - Gartman, Maj.-Gen. B., November 1932 (Box 6, Folder 24)
        - Gerua, Gen. A., includes military service record and excerpts from memoirs about and by him, including "Izmailovskaia Starina", typescript, 1936, December 1932-June 1936 (Box 6, Folder 25)
        - Gering, Maj.-Gen. E., June 1932 (Box 6, Folder 26)
        - Golovin, Lieut.-Gen. N., includes clippings, November 1930-January 1934 (Box 6, Folder 27)
        - Il'iashevich, Maj.-Gen. L., October 1932 (Box 6, Folder 28)
        - IUdenich, Lieut.-Gen. N., clippings and printed matter, 1931-1934 (Box 6, Folder 29)
        - Kal'nitskii, Lieut.-Gen. M., November 1932-February 1933 (Box 6, Folder 30)
        - Kandaurov, Col. D., December 1930 (Box 6, Folder 31)
        - Kappel, Gen. V., clipping, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 31)
        - Kermanov, Col. P., February 1933 (Box 6, Folder 32)
        - KHodnev, Col. D., May 1933 (Box 7, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 8
        - KHodorovich, General-of-Infantry N., April 1932 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        - Komorovskii, Capt. A., October 1932 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        - Kondzerovskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        - Kusonskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., October 1931-May 1932 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        - Kutepov, General-of-Infantry A., clippings, and letter of widow, L. Kusonskaia, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        - Lampe, Maj.-Gen. A. von, April 1925-June 1938 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        - Lekhovich, Lieut.-Gen. V., September 1932 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        - Liubimov, Maj.-Gen., 1932 (Box 7, Folder 9)
        - Lukomskii, Lieut.-Gen. A., December 1931 (Box 7, Folder 10)
        - Martynov, Maj.-Gen. A., includes letter of Col. P. Alkalaev-Karageorgii, December 1931-December 1932, January 1933-March 1938 (Box 7, Folder 11)
        - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., includes biographical excerpt, leaflet "Pochemu my neprimirimy" and letter of wife, September 1930-August 1936 (Box 7, Folder 12)
        - Nechvolodov, Lieut.-Gen. P., November 1936 (Box 7, Folder 13)
        - Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke, miscellaneous printed matter, 1926-1928 (Box 7, Folder 14)
        - Nikol'skii, Maj.-Gen. V., May 1932 (Box 7, Folder 15)
        - Petrushevskii, V., June 1938-September 1939 (Box 7, Folder 16)
          Available on microfilm reel 9
        - Polzikov, Maj.-Gen. M., includes material re "Drozdovtsy", September-October 1932 (Box 7, Folder 17)
        - Popov, Capt. K., December 1932 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Pototskii, Maj.-Gen., S., June 1932-July 1933 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - Pozdnyshev, S., undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
        - Pushkarev, K., May 1933-August 1939 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        - Raevskii, P., undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
        - SHatilov, General-of-Cavalry, P., October 1932-July 1943 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        - SHteifon, Gen. B., April-May 1931 (Box 8, Folder 7)
        - Simanskii, P., January 1933 (Box 8, Folder 8)
        - Skoblin, Maj.-Gen. N., November 1932 (Box 8, Folder 9)
        - Stavitskii, Lieut.-Gen. P., October 1931 (Box 8, Folder 10)
        - Tarusskii, E., July, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 11)
        - Turkul', Maj.-Gen. A., April 1932 (Box 8, Folder 12)
        - Vadbol'skii, Lieut.-Gen. N., April 1932 (Box 8, Folder 13)
        - Vinogradskii, Maj.-Gen. A., June-August 1931 (Box 8, Folder 14)
        - Vitkovskii, Lieut.-Gen. V., August 1932 (Box 8, Folder 15)
        - Zinkevich, Maj.-Gen. M., February 1933 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Clippings, 1933-1934 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Regional branches
        - Belgium, typescript and handwritten, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 18)
        - Bulgaria, printed matter, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 19)
        - Czechoslovakia, "Ob"edinenie Russkikh Voinskikh Soiuzov" and "Donskoi Komitet" (K. Asseeva), November 1942-December 1943 (Box 8, Folder 20)
        - France, typescript and handwritten, 1931-1932 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Regimental organizations
        - I-yi Armeiskii Korpus, typescript and handwritten, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 22)
        - Alekseevskii Pekhotnyi Polk, typescript, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 23)
        - Gusary
          - Aleksandriiskie, typescript, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 24)
          - Elisavetgradskie, typescript, 1931-1938 (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - Kornilovskii Udarnyi Polk, typescript and handwritten, 1925-1933 (Box 8, Folder 26)
          Available on microfilm reel 10
        - Leib-Gvardii Grenaderskii Polk, handwritten, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 27)
        - Markovskii Artilleriiskii Divizion, typescript, 1930-1937 (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Military Academies
        - Konstantinovskoe Voennoe Uchilishche, "Informatsionnyi Listok", typescript, April 1931-March 1933 (Box 8, Folder 29)
        - Kornilovskoe Voennoe Uchilishche, handwritten history and "Dessantnaia operatsiia Kornilovskago Voennago Uchilishcha. avgust", 1920 (Box 8, Folder 30)
        - Kubanskoe Generala Alekseva Voennoe Uchilishche, typescript bulletin, February-March 1931 (Box 8, Folder 31)
        - Sergievskoe Artilleriiskoe Uchilishche, "Informatsionnyi Listok", typescript, September 1932-January 1933 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Orders re R.O.V.S., typescript and printed, 1923-1931 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Reports, essays and printed matter
        - L'vov, N., Beloe Dvizhenie, Belgrade, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - Miller, Lieut.-Gen. E., Armiia, Belgrade, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - Orekhov, V., Armiia i Flot, Voennyi Spravochnik, France, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - SHatilov, Lieut.-Gen. P., "Russkaia Armiia i R.O.V.S. ot krymskoi evakuatsii do nachala goda", typescript, undated, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        - Desiatiletie Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii, Sofia, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        - "Na Dal'nem Vostoke", report re meeting of Shanghai branch, typescript, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        - Obshche-voinskii Soiuz, "Voennyia Ob"edineniia", list of local branches, tearsheet, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 8)
        - Otchet Finansovo-Kontrol'nago Komiteta ob izraskhodovanii summ, vyruchennykh ot prodazhi prosrochennykh zakladov Petrogradskoi Ssudnoi Kazny, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
        - Russkii Voennyi Kalendar'-Pamiatnik, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 10)
        - Clippings, 1930-1935 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - File 6, 1922-1937 (Boxes 9-11)
    Military associations, military science and history, Soiuz Gallipoliitsev. Includes correspondence, printed matter, and photographs.
    - Military Associations, miscellaneous material
      - Artilleriiskii ZHurnal, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - "Liventsy", 1929-1932 (Box 9, Folder 13)
        Available on microfilm reel 11
      - "Pervopokhodniki", 1922-1937 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Military science and history
      - Correspondence, clippings and pamphlets, including work by or about Gen. A. Vinogradskii, N. Golovin (Zarubezhnye Vysshie Voenno-Nauchnye Kursy), B. Gerua, IU. Danilov, P. Stavitskii, D. KHodnev, V. Domanevskii (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
    - Soiuz Gallipoliitsev
      - Corresponence
        - Orlov, G., November 1935-March 1944 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        - Rep'ev, Gen. M., See also personal correspondence of Baroness M. Vrangel', May 1931 (Box 10, Folder 4)
        - ZHukovskii-Volynskii, Col. N., includes information re Hungarian section, November 1930-September 1932 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Printed matter
        - Al'bom Karikatur, 1920-1921 (Box 10, Folder 6)
        - "Eshafot", hand-produced humor magazine, 1920? (Box 10, Folder 7)
        - "Informatsionnyi Listok", typescript
          - Brussels, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 8)
          - Gallipoli, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 9)
          - Grenoble and Paris, 1930-1932 (Box 10, Folder 10)
          - Prague, includes other, 1929-1937 (Box 10, Folder 11)
          - miscellaneous material
        - Russkie v Gallipoli, 1920-1921 (Box 11, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 12
        - Vestnik Gallipoliitsev, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 2)
        - Vestnik and Biulleten', Sofia, includes other miscellaneous material, 1927-1935 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - File 7, 1927-1935 (Boxes 11-12)
    Russian War Invalids. Includes correspondence, appeals, lists of organizations.
    - Russian War Invalids
      - Correspondence, Gen.-of-Cavalry N. Baratov, December 1931 (Box 11, Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 13
      - Zarubezhnyi Soiuz Russkikh Voennykh Invalidov
        - Protocols of meetings, typescript
          - 1927 (Box 11, Folder 7)
          - 1928 (Box 12, Folder 1)
          - 1929 (Box 12, Folder 2)
          - 1931 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        - Bulgaria, Russkii Invalid, September-October 1933 (Box 12, Folder 4)
        - Greece, miscellaneous material, including reports and photographs, 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 5)
        - Shanghai branch, miscellaneous material including Invalid's Friend, 1933-1935 (Box 12, Folder 6)
          Available on microfilm reel 14
      - "Informatsiia Glavnago Pravleniia", typescript, 1933 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - List of organizations abroad, typescript, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Appeals
        - Joffre, Maréchal J., printed leaflet, 1929 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Miscellaneous, pamplets and clippings, 1928-1932 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - File 8, 1928-1937 (Boxes 13-15)
    Russian Navy and cossacks abroad. Includes correspondence, biographical material, memoirs and printed matter.
    - Russian Navy abroad
      - Correspondence, includes biographical material and memoirs
        - Miscellaneous, handwritten, 1931-1932 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        - Bubnov, Rear-Admiral A., October 1931 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        - Garshin, M., July 1936-April 1937 (Box 13, Folder 3)
        - Kedrov, Adm. M., September 1931. Also includes clipping from CHasovoi (Box 13, Folder 4)
        - Lebedev, V., October 1932-June 1937 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        - Mashukov, Rear-Admiral N. (Box 13, Folder 6)
        - Popov, Lieut.-Gen. V., undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
        - Smirnov, Kontr-Adm. M., July 1934 (Box 13, Folder 8)
        - SHtormer, F., re Sibirskaia Flotiliia, May 1929 (Box 13, Folder 9)
        - Stakhevich, M., December 1930-July 1937 (Box 13, Folder 19)
        - Tereshchenko, S., includes clipping, "Iz Sevastopolia v Bizertu", August 1931 (Box 13, Folder 20)
        - Zon, B. von, October-December 1930 (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - General
        - "Ob"iasnitel'naia zapiska k proektu izmeneniia ustava vsezarubezhnago ob"edineniia morskikh organizatsii", typescript, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
        - List of subscribers to Morskoi ZHurnal, typescript, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 23)
        - Map: "Morskiia organizatsii za rubezhom", November 1929 (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Printed matter
        - Morskoi ZHurnal, 1929-1935 (Box 13, Folder 25-29)
          Available on microfilm reels 14-15
        - Clippings, December 1928 (Box 13, Folder 30)
          Available on microfilm reel 15
    - Cossacks
      - Correspondence, including biographical material and memoirs
        - Abramov, Lieut.-Gen. F., September 1928-April 1940 (Box 14, Folder 1)
        - Berezovskii, E., February 1935 (Box 14, Folder 2)
        - Bogaevskii, Lieut.-Gen. A., June 1932 (Box 14, Folder 3)
        - Burlin, Maj.-Gen. P., December 1933 (Box 14, Folder 4)
        - CHernyshkov, IA., includes information re Soviet conditions, October 1932 (Box 14, Folder 5)
        - CHubov, Archpriest D., typescript memoir, September 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
        - Dodonov, Col. S., undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - Dutov, Ataman A., Orenburgsk'oe Voisko, May 1933 (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - Filimonov, Lieut.-Gen. A., includes statistics on Kuban Cossacks, April, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - IAsevich, Col. P., Dec, 1933-April 1935 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - Ionov, Maj.-Gen. A., March 1929 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Kazachii Soiz v SHanhae, August 1929 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - KHripunov, M., includes information on Leib-Gvardii Atamanskii Divizion, October 1929-1931 (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Kovalev, Col. M., September 1927-September 1932 (Box 14, Folder 14)
        - Krasnov, Lieut.-Gen. P., August 1928-October 1932 (Box 14, Folder 15)
        - Lavrent'ev, K., "Vziatie g. Urgi baronom Ungernom v 1921 godu", includes unpublished memoir and other material re Baron R. Ungern-Sternberg, October 1925 (Box 14, Folder 16)
        - Lobov, Maj.-Gen. G., biography, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
          Available on microfilm reel 16
        - Malykh, K., Irkutskoe Kazach'e Voisko, September 1934 (Box 14, Folder 18)
        - Okulich, IO., includes memoir re Civil War in Siberia, copies of documents of Priamurskoe Vremennoe Pravitel'stvo and information re Enisei Cossacks abroad, August 1932, February 1933 (Box 14, Folder 19)
        - Oprits, I., August 1932 (Box 14, Folder 20)